We could tell you what it's about. But then, of course, we'd have to kill you.
Sneakers is a comedy, crime, drama film directed by Phil Alden Robinson.
When shadowy U.S.
intelligence agents blackmail a reformed computer hacker and his eccentric team of security experts into
stealing a code-breaking 'black box' from a Soviet-funded genius, they uncover a bigger conspiracy.
Now, he and his 'sneakers' must save themselves and the world
economy by retrieving the box from their blackmailers.
Bishop, played by Robert Redford.
Crease, played by Sidney Poitier.
Whistler, played by David Strathairn.
Mother, played by Dan Aykroyd.
Carl, played by River Phoenix.
Cosmo, played by Ben Kingsley.
Sneakers is a 1992 American caper thriller film directed by Phil Alden Robinson
from a screenplay co-written with Walter Parkes and Lawrence Lasker.
It stars Robert Redford, Dan Aykroyd, Ben Kingsley, Mary McDonnell,
River Phoenix, Sidney Poitier and David Strathairn.
In the film, Martin (Redford) and his group of security specialists are hired to steal a
black box but soon realize the job has nefarious and far-reaching consequences.
Lasker and Parkes first conceived Sneakers in 1981
during pre-production on WarGames (1983).
Redford was the first actor attached to the project, and he helped
recruit the remaining cast members, as well as Robinson.
Several of the characters were inspired by members of the hacking and national defense
communities, and the actors improvised several scenes during filming.
Principal photography took place on location across California, with filming taking place in San
Francisco, Oakland, Simi Valley, and the Courthouse Square backlot at Universal Studios Hollywood.
Sneakers was theatrically released in the United States on
September 11, 1992, by Universal Pictures.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics,
with praise for its humor, tone, and plot.
It grossed $105.2 million worldwide, becoming the
20th-highest-grossing film of 1992.
The film explores themes of hacker, mathematician, assignment, calm, relaxed.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.